Olga Quaranta

Phone 929-422 3044
Email quaranta.olga@gmail.com
Address Staten Island, NY 10309

SKILLS

EDI Helpdesk support, HTML, SQL, Java, Excel, Problem-Solving, IBM Sterling console management, Mapping, BP development, Photoshop, and Gimp. Experienced working on Linux and Windows operating systems. Exceptional attention to details, Client-focused, Self-Motivated, Flexible and Adaptable. Team-player who can also work independently.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Looking to leverage my development background, recent training and build upon my 3 years working experience with disparate data sets by implementing new or existing web pages, define software development best practices, master diverse frameworks, technologies, and techniques.

Highly responsible always focus to achieve exceptional results. Reliable and hardworking.

EXPERIENCE

DEVELOPER — Merge Event Solutions

Staten Island, New York. *January* 2023 - *Present* Below the projects assign to me:

- Create a memorial website for a touch screen 65" vertically mounted. The project was a page with a video and an interactive gallery with the possibility to zoom each picture and send them to an email address, using CSS, HTML and JavaScript. www.frankjprovenzano.com
- Preparing documents for entry from paper formats into computer files using scanners.
- Compiling, sorting, and verifying the accuracy of the information to prepare source data for computer entry.

IT EDI SUPPORT - Arcese Trasporti S.P.A

Rivalta di Torino, Italy. January 2021 - June 2022

Part of the Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) Support team with the following functions:

- Developed new EDI customer maps for latest clients.
- Managed a team of 5 people to lead them to solve EDI ticketing.
- Created a manual for easy understanding of issues and quick problem solving for the team.
- Conducted analysis of files from origin to destination and optimized different Trading Partners EDI mapping.
- Some of the changes prevented money loss for Arcese.
- Experienced using SQL to gather data on various scenarios and analyze it for meaningful results.
- Collaborated with team members from other IT departments to enhance the target results.

CONSULTANT — Certimeter S.R.L

Turin, Italy. February 2020 - December 2020

Consultant for Arcese Trasporti S.P.A. Part of the EDI Support team with the following duties:

- Provided online and telephone desk support regarding internal applications for operatives located in Belgium, France, Italy, Spain, Romania, and UK.
- Solved and helped requests received from Trading Partner.
- Tracked files from origin to destination and troubleshot errors.
 Intercept files received from Trading Partners that have an anomaly, modify them, and retransmit them correctly, before an operative opened a ticket.
- Change the maps to ensure that the data flow occurs correctly.

WEB DEVELOPER — Quattrolinee

Turin, Italy. July 2019 - February 2020

Supported the team in various web and e-commerce projects as front-ender and back-ender.

Developed the clients' website using WordPress, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML and JavaScript. Below the projects assign to me:

- Implemented splash page for Graphic Days 2019 and 2020 www.graphicdays.it
- Created and managed Paideia web page www.fattoriasocialepaideia.it
- Performed the landing page of Officinaundici <u>www.officinaundici.com</u>
- Updated and completed BottomUp! Torino web page <u>www.bottomuptorino.it</u>
- Updated web page www.ballettoteatroditorino.it
- Monitored and manipulated data through connection to the Database, using the Firebase and Vue.js framework for the annual Poster Heroes event www.posterheroes.org

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER — Betacom Srl

Turin, Italy. May 2012 - February 2013

Consultant at Intesa Sanpaolo Bank

Created a tool in the tray bar. The benefit was to enable the menu' items only if a specific internet connection was connected. Created manual for users and customer service.

For a different task, I updated some forms in a Visual Basic 6.0 program to insert a PDF printer, add new USB printers, and calculate the IP address of the printer with Database calls.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE — University of Turin - Turin, Oct 2011

*Thesis title: Emeroteca Virtuale (www.youtube.com/watch?v=wBCDrYFI49k (1:44))

*Academic achievements: Developed C# skill while implementing front end application on Microsoft Surface.

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE — ITIS Ettore Majorana - Grugliasco, Jul 2005

COURSES & TRAINING

JAVA FULL STACK TRAINING - Emonics Academy - September 2022 to October 2022

Java Fundamentals, MySQL, Spring Boot. Web application development with Eclipse. 306 hours of training.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TECHNICAL COURSE - ENGIM - November 2018 to July 2019

Development of web pages. HTML 5, CSS 3, Java, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Angular 2, PHP and DBMS environments. Web application development with Visual Studio Code and NetBeans.

1000 hours included 300 hours of internships at the Quattrolinee company.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Italian: native language

English: proficient (reading, writing, comprehend, speaking)

HOBBIES

Cooking. Crafting. Reading. Video Games. Taking pictures with my DSLR camera and do post-production.